Guide to the Aristide Cavaillé-Coll papers, 1833-1885, 1970s RL.10022
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Aristide Caviallé-Coll papers
1833-1885, 1970s
bulk
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Aristide Caviallé-Coll
RL.10022
9 Linear Feet
Aristide Caviallé-Coll was a French organ builder and musician. The collection includes unbound, full-size prints from microfilm of letters, monographs, first drafts, contracts, and indexes which reflect the extent of Caviallé-Coll's work in France, Europe, and the Americas, as well as his incorporation of technological innovations into his instruments. This material was used by Professor Fenner Douglass in his book "Caviallé-Coll and the Musicians; a Documented Account of the First Thirty Years in Organ Building," and includes the author's index cards and notebooks.
Biographical/Historical note
Aristide Caviallé-Coll was a French organ builder and musician.
Collection Overview
The collection includes unbound, full-size prints from microfilm of letters, monographs, first drafts, contracts, and indexes which reflect the extent of Caviallé-Coll's work in France, Europe and the Americas, as well as his incorporations of technological innovations into his instruments. The material in this collection was used by Professor Fenner Douglass in his book "Caviallé-Coll and the Musicians; a Documented Account of the First Thirty Years in Organ Building," and the collection includes the author's index cards and notebooks.
Provenance
The Aristide Caviallé-Coll papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in several accessions as a gift beginning in 1979.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Organ (Musical Instrument) -- Construction -- History.; Organ builders -- Correspondence.; Aristide Caviallé-Coll; Douglass, Fenner
- Aristide Caviallé-Coll papers
  - Information Folder; Etats des Orgues (1838-1858), parts. 1-2; Devis I (1833-1840), part 1, 1833-1858 (Box 1)
  - Devis II (1841-1845), parts 1-2; Devis III, (1845-1849), part. 1, 1841-1849 (Box 2)
  - Devis III (1845-1849), part 2; Devis IV (1850-1856) parts 1-2, 1845-1856 (Box 3)
  - Devis V (1856-1859), parts 1-2; Marches 2 (1863-1878), part 1, 1856-1878 (Box 4)
  - Marches 2 (1863-1878), part 2; Lettres I (1840-1844), parts 1-2; Lettres II (1844-1848), part 1, 1840-1878 (Box 5)
  - Lettres II (1844-1848), part 2; Lettres III (1848-1851), parts 1-2; Lettres IV (1851-1855), part 1, 1844-1855 (Box 6)
  - Lettres IV (1851-1855), parts 2-3; Lettres V (1855-1859), parts 1-2, 1851-1859 (Box 7)
  - Lettres V (1855-1859), part 3; Lettres VI (1859), parts 1-2 (Box 8)
  - Loose correspondence and notes: 1838-1885; Personnel de la maison A. Cavaille-Coll (1876); Dossier of scales in effects of Jean La Preste; Miscellany; Indices - Letters (Notebook); Notebook, 1838-1855 (Box 9)
  - Index Cards, 1970s (Box 10)